Guide to the Eleanor Gibson Papers, 1906-1999, 1935-1999 (bulk)
Gibson, Eleanor Papers, 1906-1999, 1935-1999 (bulk)
- Series IV. Talks, Lectures, and Classes
  - Concept Formation Conference, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Learning, Remembering and Forgetting, conference at Princeton, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Perceptual Learning Seminar, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Berkeley paper:Perceptual Learning in Educational Situations, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Motivation: perception of face and people 1968-1978 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Comparative psychology 1970 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Scanning and reading 1970-1976 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Colloquium on Meaning, Fall 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Psychology 309, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Attention: readings 1972-1978 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Slides for Ecological Optics, 1972-1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Stroop, Kukish and Golintoff Rosinski 1972-1982 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Environmental layout: lecture notes 1973-1976 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Pictorial perception: course outlines, notes 1973-1979 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Set and selection 1973-1979 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Learning conference 1973-1989 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Course on Perceptual Learning, Fall 1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Psychology 309, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Language development: notes, reprints 1975-1979 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Psychology 209, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Psychology 308: Perceptual Learning, Fall 1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Preadapted coordinations: perception of objects: notes 1976-1979 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Preadapted coordinations: unity 1976-1980 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Attention, development of: course materials 1977 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Psych 309 course outlines 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Psych 309 & 263B course outlines 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - History of Developmental Psychology seminar at Cornell, Fall 1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - History of Developmental Psychology seminar at Cornell, Fall 1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Perceptual Learning and Development course at UCONN, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Psychology 309 Notes (UC Davis), 1978 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Pictorial perception: course outlines, notes, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Psychology 263B: course outlines, notes (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Attention seminar 1979 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - EPA Symposium:Women in Academia, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minnesota Seminar, Fall 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Echoic Memory 1981 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Ecological Approach to Perception and Perceptual Development (S.Carolina), ca. 1981 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Conference on Event Perception, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Lecture and Conference notes from Institute of Psychology, Beijing, China, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - William James Seminar: Psych 561, Spring 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Penn Seminar, Spring 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Penn Workshop Paper, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Seminar on Perception and Perceptual Development: Historical perspectives and the ecological approach, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Uppsala Conference, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Dartmouth Seminar on Child Development, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Quick Talk on Ecological Approach vs. Constructivist 1986 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - University of South Carolina commencement speech 1987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Trieste Symposium, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Emory Colloquium Paper and Slides on Mobility, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Exploratory behavior 1988 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Geneva Talk - Affordances in Perceptual Development, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Miami University of Ohio Conference, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Perceptual Learning Seminar at Emory, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Cornell Colloquium, Spring 1991 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Cornell Centennial Paper on Information, July 1991 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - ISSBD Symposium on Dynamic Systems in Development, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - University of Minnesota Conference, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Minnesota Seminar, Spring 1992 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Notes and Overheads for Affordances Colloquium, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Duke Colloquium, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Perceptual development colloquium 1993 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Prolegomena Paper for Storrs Conference, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - USC Seminar, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Virginia Tech Talk with Slides, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Cognitive Group Talk (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Conference on Pre-School Education papers (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Demonstrations for Introductory Course: Acquisition and Extinction of Anticipatory Responses (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Demonstrations for Introductory Course: Retroactive Inhibition (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Early Development Lecture (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Emory Colloquium Talk (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Flow Pattern Symposium (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Guiding Locomotion, Poster and Slides (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Information Based Theory of Perceptual Development: Notes and Slides (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Iowa Talk (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - James J. Gibson Information Lecture with slides (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Jill Kerr Conway Talk (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Lecture on the History of Developmental Psychology (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lectures on Conditioning (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Maternal Behavior Lecture (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Miami University of Ohio Paper: Learning to Perceive or Perceiving to Learn? (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Slides (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Motivation: differential rearing (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Notes for Colloquium on Distance Experts - WWII (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Reading Conference Paper:Analysis of the Reading Process as Perceptual Learning (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reading lists for majors and minors in perceptual development (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Speeches on Generalization and Discrimination Learning (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Trends in perceptual development (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Visual Cliff photographs and negatives (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Walkway photograph and slide (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Possible mutations [overheads for teaching] (Box 18, Folder 28)
- Series V. Experiments and Grants
  - Fear Schedule: Experiment on the fears of college women, ca. 1940-1945 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Anger Survey Checklists, ca. 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Thematic Apperception Test, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Vocational Interest Tests, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Students' descriptions of Anger, notes, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Students' descriptions of Anger, notes, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Data on Emotionally Toned Sylloqisms (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Distance Estimation Experiment on Cornell Arts Quadrangle, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - E.J.G. and R.D. Walk NSF grant proposal, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Ideas for new research and experiments, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Rearing experiments, receptor fields, microelectrode recording 1963-1975 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Reading Grant: First Proposal and Award, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Word-Picture Experiment: Articles, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Anagram Experiment, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Anagram Experiment, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Event Perception Experimental set up used by Mundy-Castle illustration photo, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Reading Grant: Quarterly Progress Reports, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Rigid Motion vs. Deformation, experiment data (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Scanning Experiment with Category Structure: Punch cards, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Reading Grant: Equipment, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Redundant Cues experiment, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Scanning Experiment with Category Structure, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Scanning Experiment with Category Structure, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Scanning Experiment with Category Structure, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Scanning Experiment with Category Structure, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Scanning Experiment with Category Structure, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Scanning Experiment with Category Structure, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Scanning Experiment with Category Structure, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Scanning Experiment with Category Structure, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Scanning Experiment with Category Structure, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Scanning Experiment with Orthographic Structure, ca. 1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Reading Grant: Contract extension, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Word-Picture Experiment: Notes, data, paper summary, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Letter and Color Redundancy Experiment Data sheets, ca. 1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Infant Motion Study, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Spencer Foundation Grant proposal and correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Alphabet Experiment (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 5" Floppy Disk:Walkway Data From Mainframe, February 19, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Aperture obstacle film [16mm film] (Box 20)
  - Events [videocassette] (Box 20)
  - Fowler, Vicki: experiments [videocassette] (Box 20)
  - Habituation: Johansson film [videocassette] (Box 20)
  - Hole/patch tapes: data mixed up with other studies [videocassette] (Box 20)
  - Infant exploration of objects (Palmer) [videocassette] (Box 20)
  - Square moving room infants #1-2 [videocassette ] (Box 20)
  - Moving room #3-5 [videocassette ] (Box 20)
  - Optical transitions [videocassette] (Box 20)
  - Total demo [videocassette], 1985 (Box 20)
  - A visual cliff [videocassette] (Box 20)
  - Blank [videocassette] (Box 20)
  - Walkway #1-8, 10-14, 17-20 [videocassettes] (Box 21)
  - New walkway demo [videocassette] (Box 21)
- Series VI. Book publication materials
  - Psychology of Reading
    - Chapter 1: miscellaneous material (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 1: Discriminability of Letters (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 1: Articles, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Chapter 1: Article- Reading Between the Lines: A Study of Selective Attention in Good and Poor Readers, Dale M. Willows, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Chapter 2 material, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 29--30)
    - Chapter 3: Language Acquisition material, 1955-1975 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Chapter 5: Writing Systems material, 1932, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Chapter 5: Writing Systems material, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Chapter 5: Writing Systems material, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Chapter 6: Word Recognition material (Box 2, Folder 35--36)
    - Chapter 6: Word Recognition material, 1897, 1950-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1--7)
    - Chapter 7: Prereading and Pretraining Skills, 1955-1976 (Box 3, Folder 8--14)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 3, Folder 15--19)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 8: Initial Reading and Decoding, 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 9: Transition, 1966-1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 10: Learning from Reading, 1917, 1947-1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 10: Learning from Reading, 1917, 1947-1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 10: Learning from Reading, 1917, 1947-1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 10: Learning from Reading, 1917, 1947-1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 11: Models, 1968-1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 11: Models, 1968-1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 11: Models, 1968-1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 11: Models, 1968-1974 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Part III, 1960-1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Part III, 1960-1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Part III, 1960-1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Part III, 1960-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Part III, 1960-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Part III, 1960-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Part III, 1960-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Part III, 1960-1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Part III, 1960-1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Part III, 1960-1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - General Reviews, 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - General Reviews, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - General Reviews, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - General Reviews, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - An Odyssey in Learning and Perception
    - Perceptual development: historical perspective (chapter 1) 1970-1995 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Methods and motivation in infants (Chapter 3, part II) 1964-1995 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Perceptual development (Chapter 4) 1968-1998 (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
    - Attention in perceptual development (Chapter IV) 1972-1979 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Attention and perception (Chapter V) 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Locomotion (Chapter 7) 1956-1995 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Beyond infancy (Chapter X) 1990-1996 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Perception in language: information in speech (Chapter 13) 1994 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Illustrations, figures 1992 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Publisher correspondence 1991 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Indices: author, subject (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Preface, introduction 1990 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Permissions received 1983-1990 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Works cited 1932-1987 (Box 19, Folder 21-23)
    - Odyssey file cards ("most up to date") (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Odyssey ("most up to date") (Box 19, Folder 25)
- Series VII. Miscellaneous
  - Awards for Distinguished Scientific Achievement, (list) 1999 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Review of paper, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence re papers by others 2001-2002 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Language and perception, George A. Miller and Philip N. Johnson-Laird [book] 1976 (Box 22)
  - Monographs of the Society for Research in Child Development: Basic cognitive processes in children, edited by John C. Wright and Jerome Kagan [book] 1976 (Box 22)
  - Studies in learning 1950-1960, Eleanor J. Gibson [2 copies, book] 1950-1960 (Box 22)
  - Child psychology, edited by Harold W. Stevenson with assistance of Jerome Kagan and Charles Spiker [book] 1963 (Box 22)
  - Toward a literate society, John B. Carroll and Jeanne S. Chall [book] 1975 (Box 22)
  - Analysis of reading skill, Harry Levin, Eleanor J. Gibson, James J. Gibson [book] 1968 (Box 22)
  - Communicating by language, edited by James F. Kavanagh [book] 1968 (Box 22)
  - Analysis of reading skill: a program of basic and applied research, Harry Levin, Eleanor J. Gibson, James J. Gibson [report] 1968 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Toward an ecological theory of autism, Katherine A. Loveland [paper] 2000 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - The relationship between perceptual development and reading skill, Eleanor J. Gibson [report] 1971 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Audio Cassette - E.G. Boring's Society of Experimental Psychologists / Edward B. Titchener centennial speech, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Audio Recording of same E.G. Boring speech (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - VHS - The Man Who Made Up His Mind, BBC Horizon, January 1994 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - VHS - Optic Motions (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Audio Cassette - unmarked (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - 3" Floppy Disk - unformatted (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Newspaper, "The way to the brain", 1972 (Folder 1)